<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Blog on Amish Kumar Naidu</title>
    <link>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Blog on Amish Kumar Naidu</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; 2022 Amish K. Naidu</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 02 Jul 2017 08:14:51 +0700</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Writing custom serde deserializers, the easy way</title>
      <link>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/serde-deserialize/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jan 2021 19:34:17 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/serde-deserialize/</guid>
      <description>Serde is a great library for serializing/deserializing in Rust. It allows you to directly convert rust data structures using a few attributes. Most of the time, It Just Works ™ and when it doesn&amp;rsquo;t, you can write your own serializers or deserializers!
Problem at hand: There exists a type which can be parsed from a string but serde has no built in support for it. For the purposes of an example, let&amp;rsquo;s say the type is std::net::IpAddr and forget that serde has support for it already.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hugo</title>
      <link>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2019 00:57:32 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/hugo/</guid>
      <description>I finally have a new post after about two years!
This is the customary blog post where I talk about moving to the new static site generator.
Hugo.
This is way more flexible and easier to maintain than my previous setup, which was a hand-crafted website written using vanilla HTML and CSS. After keeping it for about 4 years I realized it was time to move on. It was a bit of a pain to add anything using raw HTML.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Let&#39;s Make an Extremely Readable Birthday Melody, the IOCCC Way</title>
      <link>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/obfuscate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Apr 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/obfuscate/</guid>
      <description>Obfuscate: tr.v. -cated, -cating, -cates.
i. To render obscure.
ii. To darken. To confuse: his emotions obfuscated his judgment. [Lat. obfuscare, to darken : ob(intensive) + Lat. fuscare, to darken &amp;lt; fuscus, dark.] -obfuscation n. obfuscatory adj (taken from IOCCC)
The Why You learn lesser known aspects of the language Job security. Write obfuscated code and make sure no one else can maintain it but you! It&amp;rsquo;s fun. &amp;rsquo;nuff said. The Plan We&amp;rsquo;ll be making a small C program which generates samples of a song (we&amp;rsquo;ll stick with the &amp;lsquo;Happy Birthday&amp;rsquo; song), whose output will then be piped to aplay.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The file you can&#39;t read on Windows</title>
      <link>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/file-read-bug/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/file-read-bug/</guid>
      <description>I stumbled on this bug with my NES emulator where the ROMs won&amp;rsquo;t open under Windows but had worked without a hitch on Linux and macOS.
I had been developing on Linux and occasionally it tested on macOS. So it wasn&amp;rsquo;t until quite late into the development that I found that the emulator can&amp;rsquo;t open any ROM files on Windows.
This bug had me really perpexled, for why the emulator breaks only under Windows.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Connect and control your media player with python and dbus using MPRIS</title>
      <link>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/dbus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Jun 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://amish.naidu.dev/blog/dbus/</guid>
      <description>In this guide we&amp;rsquo;ll be using Python 3 although you may be able to apply this to Python 2.4 and above with minor adjustments. Since D-Bus is only used by Linux and BSD distributions, needless to say, this will only work with *nix systems
We&amp;rsquo;ll connect to a media player which implements the Media Player Remote Interfacing Specification or MPRIS for short. Most popular players like Audacious, Amarok, Clementine, VLC etc will work.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
